Guide to the Puebla Archives
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Civil Cases, 1567-1878; Series III
  - Petition to the governor by Juana Victoriana Solano that her husband Pedro Solano be released from prison, 1800 (Box 37, Folder 881)
  - Complaint filed by Juan Domingo Somacuento against the intendant concerning the persecution by Fernando Sánchez of his wife, 1800 (Box 38, Folder 882)
  - Concerning confiscation of aguardiente, 1800 - 1801 (Box 38, Folder 883)
  - Petition by the Convent of San Agustín that a testimony be administered, 1800 - 1803 (Box 38, Folder 884)
  - Juan de la Buena vs. Mariano Gómez, concerning his carrying out of his office, 1801 (Box 38, Folder 885)
  - José Juárez, debt to José Orozco, 1801 (Box 38, Folder 886)
  - Petition by María Lorenza that her husband Mateo de Jesús be released from prison, concerning a debt, 1801 (Box 38, Folder 887)
  - Action taken upon Rafael Mangino's petition that the Municipal Council grant him a certificate of census (taxes?), 1801 - 1803 (Box 38, Folder 888)
  - Testament concerning death of Juana Cortez de Galvez, wife of Santiago Carreto, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 889)
  - Petition by Melchora that two confiscated sheep be returned to him, not being smuggled, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 890)
  - Juan Manuel Muñoz vs. Jesús María y José concerning payment of a sum, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 891)
  - Case concerning smuggling of tobacco against Fastor de la Renta, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 892)
  - Petition by Manuel Santos Romay concerning his case against José Vicente Zagado concerning payment of a debt, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 893)
  - Concerning confiscation of aguardiente from Joséf Bondillo, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 894)
  - Petition by José Santiago Ruíz concerning valuation of a house he administered, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 895)
  - Petition concerning the wait on cases concerning confiscation of Juan Torre and José Gordillo, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 896)
  - Decree concerning aguardiente confiscated by three guards, 1802 (Box 38, Folder 897)
  - José Felipe Saldana vs. José Antonio Nunez concerning will, 1802 - 1819 (Box 38, Folder 898)
  - Debt owed to Vicente Manero by Francisco Morales -petition and forgiving of, 1803 (Box 38, Folder 899)
  - Case concerning payment of 2,000 pesos for one year's service to Manuel Rayon, bondsman of Fernando Alvarez Godoy, 1803 (Box 38, Folder 900)
  - Claim by Francisco Antonio Rodríguez concerning the loss of tobacco, 1803 (Box 38, Folder 901)
  - Petition by José Rafael Rosete concerning his store, 1803 (Box 38, Folder 902)
  - Case concerning four bottles of aguardiente found by José Isita, no defendant, 1803-1805 (Box 38, Folder 903)
  - Investigation of payments made by Rafael Manginot Francisco Adorno to Pedro Ladrón de Quevara, 1803 - 1805 (Box 38, Folder 904)
  - Action concerning charging María Joséfa Duran de Huerta a 50 p. fine for having an unlicensed pulpería, 1803 - 1809 (Box 38, Folder 905)
  - Action concerning charging Juan Evangelista Albarado 50 p. fine for having an unlicensed pulpería, 1803 - 1809 (Box 38, Folder 906)
  - Action concerning rents of Espinal Ranch, 1803 - 1809 (Box 38, Folder 907)
  - Action concerning fining José Merino 50 pesos for having an unlicensed pulpería, 1803 - 1809 (Box 38, Folder 908)
  - Case concerning exacting 10 pesos, 3 r's owed to the Real Hacienda from Ignacio Victoria, 1803 - 1809 (Box 38, Folder 909)
  - Fourth notebook concerning sale made by Manuel Vásquez Gastelu, 1803 - 1814 (Box 38, Folder 910)
  - Proceedings to exact from Pedro García de Larracilla 191 pesos, 2 r's, 9 g's owed to the Ramo de Media Annata, 1803 - 1815 (Box 38, Folder 911)
  - Proceedings to exact from Juan Gonzáles Escalante 639 pesos, 2 r's, 9 g's owed, 1803 - 1815 (Box 38, Folder 912)
  - Manuel Martínez Gómez vs. Manuel Vásquez Gastelu concerning a payment of a debt, 1803 - 1815 (Box 38, Folder 913)
  - Case of the citizens of San Damian Tetoloc, Maxcala opposing possession of the hacienda San Juan Tlixco, 1803 - 1819, n.d (much earlier) (Box 38, Folder 914)
  - Action to exact from Pedro Nicolás Cadrecha 6 pesos owed to the Ramo de Media Annata, 1804 (Box 38, Folder 915)
  - Testimony by Gertrúdis de Castañeda concerning the health of Francisco Zamacona, 1804 (Box 38, Folder 916)
  - Decree concerning Ignacio Paredes signed Conde de la Cadena, 1804 (Box 38, Folder 917)
  - Concerning payment to Ramon de la Rosa, 1804 (Box 38, Folder 918)
  - Bartolomé de Rosas vs. Antonio García Mellado concerning a sum of money, 1804 (Box 38, Folder 919)
  - Concerning 2,000 pesos paid to José María Murguta, bondsman of José Manuel Ronderos for administering tobacco in Amosoque, 1804 (Box 38, Folder 920)
  - Case presented by Ministers of the Royal Hacienda concerning José Manuel Ronderos for his work with pulperías, 1804 - 1807 (Box 39, Folder 921)
  - Action initiated by the Minister of the Royal Hacienda concerning demanding of Manuel Francisco Sánchez the goods of the community of Tecali, 1803, 1804 - 1813 (Box 39, Folder 922)
  - Case presented by the Ministers of the Royal Hacienda, that José Lubian pay 34 pesos, 4 r's, 9 g's from the taxes he collected, 1804 - 1815 (Box 39, Folder 923)
  - Decree by the count of La Cacena concerning a debt of the mayor, 1805 (Box 39, Folder 924)
  - Manuel Sánchez Viscaino and the Convent of Sras. Religiosas Clarisas de la Villa de Atlixco vs. Francisco Xavier Cavallero, 1805 (Box 39, Folder 925)
  - José de Ramos, petition concerning his hacienda, ranch and horses, 1805 (Box 39, Folder 926)
  - Power conferred by María Joaquina Ravanillo to Mariano Ramirez de la Cuesta, 1805 (Box 39, Folder 927)
  - Proceedings of the reunion of the marriage of José Francisco Santisteban and María Gertrúdis Pinzon, 1805 -1806 (Box 39, Folder 928)
  - Case initiated by the Royal Junta Superior concerning taxes on aguardiente, Yzucar, 1805 -1806 (Box 39, Folder 929)
  - Case presented by Ministers of the Royal Hacienda vs. the administrators of Tlixco and Xochimilco concerning rights of pulperías, 1805 - 1815 (Box 39, Folder 930)
  - Confiscation of 6 oz. of tobacco from María Gertrúdis Díaz by the inspector José Tomariz y Rivera, 1806 (Box 39, Folder 931)
  - Confiscation of cigars from José Mariano Flórez by the inspector José de Tamapiz y Rivera and his assistants, 1806 (Box 39, Folder 932)
  - Transferral of authority from María de Jesús Gallardo to José Ramirez de Arellano, 1805 (Box 39, Folder 933)
  - Petition by Miguél Hidalgo de Vaena for José Mariano Borja, that he be released from prison, 1806 (Box 39, Folder 934)
  - Petition by José Domingo Rangel, mayor, that his tenure be accredited, 1806 (Box 39, Folder 935)
  - Citizens of San Juan Bautista vs. the Hacienda of San Luis del Mente asking for the money owed them, to be used for the church, 1806 - 1809 (Box 39, Folder 936)
  - Lieutenant in charge of taxes vs. Andrés Avendano and José Salgade, 1806 - 1812 (Box 39, Folder 937)
  - Preparatory to the consideration of the inventory of the estate of the late Pedro de la Rosa Aire y Contreras, 1806 - 1813 (Box 39, Folder 938)
  - Sale by Miguél José Antonio García and José Mariano García (brothers) as heirs of Ana María Gonzáles, 1806 - 1815 (Box 39, Folder 939)
  - Case concerning the confiscation of nine shipments of flour, 1806 - 1815 (Box 39, Folder 940)
  - Action to exact from José María Falcos debts owed to the public hacienda, 1806 - 1850 (Box 39, Folder 941)
  - Cristóbal Blanco concerning subrogation of the bond lent by Miguél Chávez, 1807 (Box 39, Folder 942)
  - Case initiated by José Antonio Toronda concerning Micaela Pavía's being transferred to Mexico City, 1807 (Box 39, Folder 943)
  - Case concerning valuation of lands of the Indians, 1807 (Box 39, Folder 944)
  - Action to charge José Ignacio Beltran 164 p's, 2 r's, 6 g's owed to the Royal Hacienda, 1807 - 1815 (Box 39, Folder 945)
  - Action to exact from Joaquín de Ovande and Nicolás Rosales taxes owed, 1807 - 1815 (Box 39, Folder 946)
  - Action initiated by the Ministers of the Royal Hacienda to exact tax money in his possession from the subdelegate of Guachinaco, 1808 (Box 39, Folder 947)
  - Second testimony concerning the granting of a sum of money from the Fund of Santiago de Echevarria to the Sta. Iglesia Catedral, 1808 (Box 39, Folder 948)
  - Second testimony of the 16th book, concerning petition by the attorneys of the late Santiago José de Echevarria, Bishop, to investigate the extent of his estate, 1808 (Box 39, Folder 949)
  - Fourth testimony of the 16th book, concerning petition by the attorneys of the late Santiago José de Echevarria, Bishop, to investigate the extent of his estate, 1808 (Box 39, Folder 950)
  - Ana María Calva vs. José Antonio Irarde y Andrade concerning her property, 1809 (Box 40, Folder 951)
  - Second testimony, 1st book concerning appraisal of the estate of the late Santiago José de Echeverria, 1809 (Box 40, Folder 952)
  - Decree concerning petition by María Joséfa Espino Barrios that her son José María Camacho be released from prison, 1809 (Box 40, Folder 953)
  - Anselmo Rodríguez Balda vs. Franco Gómez concerning the finances of the Convent of San Geronimo, 1809 (Box 40, Folder 954)
  - Petition by citizens of Tzinacantepec concerning those who make pulque, 1810 (Box 40, Folder 955)
  - Incident relating to the testamentary execution of the will of Juan Coravito, the sale of a house to Miguél Carrera, 1810 - 1818 (Box 40, Folder 956)
  - Case against José Tamaris y Rivera concerning debt owed to the Royal Hacienda, 1810 - 1819 (Box 40, Folder 957)
  - Rafael Jiménez, auction of two ranches, 1810 - 1820 (Box 40, Folder 958)
  - Transferral of authority from Joséf Gamboa to his wife Juana Saenz, 1811 (Box 40, Folder 959)
  - Action concerning inventory of the estate of Manuel Daza, copy, 1811 (Box 40, Folder 960)
  - Juan Ignacio Morales, Indian, vs. Ignacio Nunez concerning payment of his salary, 1811 (Box 40, Folder 961)
  - Concerning pulque, Santa Ana Xalmimilco, 1811 (Box 40, Folder 962)
  - Manuel Díaz de Bonilla vs. Ana Joaquina Peréz concerning payment of a debt, 1811 - 1812 (Box 40, Folder 963)
  - Chaplaincy founded by Nicolás de Castro Sandova vs. Ana Joséfa Pavon concerning payment of a debt, 1812 (Box 40, Folder 964)
  - Petition by María Joséfa Fernández de Nieva, widow of Francisco Torres that her ranch, taken by the Revolutiona Ries, be returned, 1812 (Box 40, Folder 965)
  - Case against Fernando Zarripa, 1812 (Box 40, Folder 966)
  - Mr. P Prior of the Convent of San Agustín vs. the hacienda of Acocotla, 1812 - 1819 (Box 40, Folder 967)
  - Petition by Manuel Carranza that he be allowed time to pay his debt as he is now suffering from the plague, 1813 (Box 40, Folder 968)
  - Felipe Machado vs. Matias Valverde concerning payment of a debt, 1813 - 1816 (Box 40, Folder 969)
  - Petition by Diego Gonzáles concerning separation from his wife María Albina Juárez, 1814 (Box 40, Folder 970)
  - Proceedings initiated by petition by José Manuel Serrano that a meeting be held with his creditors for revisions, 1814 - 1823 (Box 40, Folder 971)
  - Petition by Rafael de la Cueva that he be given a certified copy of the will of his father, 1815 (Box 40, Folder 972)
  - Petition of José María Fuentes concerning the estate of his late father, 1815 (Box 40, Folder 973)
  - Pedro Rodríguez Lantea vs. Vicenta Díaz Cruz concerning a sum of money, 1816 (Box 40, Folder 974)
  - Tomás Murphy vs. Juan Bautista Lobos, concerning payment of a sum, 2nd and 3rd notebooks, 1817 (Box 41, Folder 975)
  - Petition by Cristóbal Nava, that he be released from prison where he is held for alleged smuggling, 1817 (Box 41, Folder 976)
  - Case against several accused of smuggling seeds, 1817 - 1822 (Box 41, Folder 977)
  - Action to exact from Ignacio Armijo a debt taken by the hacienda of Altonsina Atlixco, 1817 - 1823 (Box 41, Folder 978)
  - Authorization of the sale of land by Juan Nepoceno Calua to Diego Mariano Cuesta, 1818 (Box 41, Folder 979)
  - Petition by Manuel Ignacio de Ruanova concerning the inspector, 1818 (Box 41, Folder 980)
  - Ana Hidalgo de Vargas Villanueva vs. Antonio García Cazo, her husband, concerning their marriage, 1818 - 1823 (Box 41, Folder 981)
  - Petition by Miguél Antonio that he be released from prison, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 982)
  - Petition by Manuel Juan Carrillo concerning permission to slaughter cattle, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 983)
  - Petition by Joaquín Huerta that he be granted permission to slaughter his cattle, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 984)
  - Petition by Francisco Lamego concerning debts of rents, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 985)
  - José Francisco Losada vs. José Pedro Aguilar concerning payment of a debt, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 986)
  - Petition by Juan Moctezuma that he be granted permission to kill 150 head of cattle, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 987)
  - Petition by José María Oronzono that he be given permission to kill 130 head of cattle, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 988)
  - Petition by José Mariano Ortíz concerning permission to slaughter his cattle, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 989)
  - Power authorized by Ignacia and María Joaquina Rabanillo to Genero Cavenez, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 990)
  - Petition by Joaquín Ramirez that he be granted permission to kill 300 head of cattle, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 991)
  - Francisco Antonio Telles, concerning the confiscation of some leather and material, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 992)
  - Decrees concerning taxation of pulquerías, 1819 (Box 41, Folder 993)
  - Sale of a ranch by Manuel María Acevo, 1820 (Box 41, Folder 994)
  - Petition by José Antonio Rico that a pulquería, found to have a rotten building, be condemned, 1820 (Box 41, Folder 995)
  - Concerning sale of a house of the estate of the late José Bocarando, 1820 (Box 41, Folder 996)
  - Petition by Antonio María Yanez concerning aguardiente be confiscated from the neighborhood of Sta. Angel, 1820 (Box 41, Folder 997)
  - Nicolás Mariano Creitun petition concerning decisions of the creditors of an estate, 1820 - 1824 (Box 41, Folder 998)
  - Petition by José Francisco de Arcos concerning permission to slaughter goats, 1821 (Box 41, Folder 999)
  - Petition by Juan Mariano Dominguez concerning permission to slaughter his sheep and goats, 1821 (Box 41, Folder 1000)
  - Petition by Mariano Marquoz concerning permission to slaughter his sheep and goat, 1821 (Box 41, Folder 1001)
  - Petition by Juan Osio that he be granted permission to slaughter his sheep and goats, 1821 (Box 41, Folder 1002)
  - Juan Agustín Segura vs. Luciano Cortes concerning a sum of money, 1821 (Box 41, Folder 1003)
  - Agustín and Vargas, guards, vs. José Marcelo Chávez concerning his store, 1822 (Box 41, Folder 1004)
  - Case against José María Hernández and María Rodríguez discovered in the tax division, 1822 (Box 41, Folder 1005)
  - Certificate of payment received from Ignacio Paz for pulque, 1822 (Box 41, Folder 1006)
  - Concerning patrimony received from Bárbara Torres, 13,990 pesos, 4 r's, 1822 - 1824 (Box 41, Folder 1007)
  - Case initiated by Francisco Armentia concerning auction of his house Aguayo, 1822 - 1827 (Box 41, Folder 1008)
  - Division of the Estate (descended by primogeniture) of José María Obando, 1822 - 1828 (Box 41, Folder 1009)
  - Ana Hidalgo Villanueva vs. her husband, Antonio García, that he return the beds which are hers, 1823 (Box 41, Folder 1010)
  - Will of Joséfa Marin, 1823 (Box 41, Folder 1011)
  - Case against Francisco José de Rauamillo, mayor, concerning money owed, 1823 - 1832 (Box 41, Folder 1012)
  - Case against the guard of Marcelo Chávez for improper carrying out of his job, 1824 (Box 41, Folder 1013)
  - Account of the Estate of the late Juan Coleoqua, 1824 (Box 41, Folder 1014)
  - Case against Francisco Gutiérrez for smuggling aguardiente, 1824 (Box 41, Folder 1015)
  - Petition by José Mariano Ortíz that he be paid for services as an attorney, 1824 (Box 41, Folder 1016)
  - Case against José Eugenio, mayor of Sta. María Xolalpa concerning fining, 1825 (Box 41, Folder 1017)
  - Action concerning wheat belonging to Antonio Gallegos, 1825 (Box 41, Folder 1018)
  - Decrees concerning case against Rafael Molina, 1825 (Box 41, Folder 1019)
  - Petition by María Manuela Gómez that José María Pomero, her son be released from prison, 1826 (Box 41, Folder 1020)
  - Owners of the ranches Tezizapa and Cruitizizilio vs. the citizens of Chicontepec, 1826 (Box 41, Folder 1021)
  - Complaints of infractions of the Federal Military Constitution, 1826 (Box 41, Folder 1022)
  - Petition by Joaquín Ysunza, silversmith, concerning a vessel, 1827 (Box 42, Folder 1023)
  - Case concerning debts owed by Joaquín Estevez, 1827-1840 (Box 42, Folder 1024)
  - Case against José Antonio Guaneros, José Antonio Barrera and Joaquín Medina for excesses against Teodoro Calderón, 1828 (Box 42, Folder 1025)
  - Empty notebook with the title: Ignacio Flores vs. the Mayor of Palmar, 1828 (Box 42, Folder 1026)
  - Petition by Mariano Lascano that he be released from prison, being innocent, 1828 (Box 42, Folder 1027)
  - Investigation of what Petrona Navarro is said to have buried in her house, 1828 - 1829 (Box 42, Folder 1028)
  - Case against Juan Pelaez, working for Francisco Gutiérrez, 1828 - 1829 (Box 42, Folder 1029)
  - Case concerning the will of Ignacio Osorio of Tamapache, 1829 (Box 42, Folder 1030)
  - Case presented by José Silvestre Cisneros concerning aguardiente he was found in possession of, 1829 (Box 42, Folder 1031)
  - Petition concerning wait on his case by Basilio Antonio, 1830 (Box 42, Folder 1032)
  - Toribio Cacalo vs. Miguél Ibanez concerning payment of a sum, 1830 - 1836 (Box 42, Folder 1033)
  - Complaint by Francisco Vera concerning plot of land, 1831 (Box 42, Folder 1034)
  - Case against María Guadalupe Pedraza for recurring drunkenness, 1832 (Box 42, Folder 1035)
  - Petition by Bárbara Lozano that her husband Rafael Zeron and nephew Francisco Baez be released from prison, being innocent, 1833 (Box 42, Folder 1036)
  - Miguél Tenorio vs. José Miguél Sánchez, mayor, concerning a fine, 1833 (Box 42, Folder 1037)
  - Petition by Clemente Solano concerning deeds of water, 1834 (Box 42, Folder 1038)
  - Case concerning confiscation of sugar belonging to Cristóbal Castillo, 1835 (Box 42, Folder 1039)
  - Action concerning petition of Ignacio Fuentes requesting a license to move the irrigation water rights bought from María Dolores Gutiérrez, 1835 (Box 42, Folder 1040)
  - Case against Nicolás Mariano Cureno, found in possession of aguardiente, 1835 (Box 42, Folder 1041)
  - Case concerning arrest of Francisco by Rafael Saavedra for undocumented possession of yellow ochre and verdigris, 1835 (Box 42, Folder 1042)
  - Case concerning José María Lara and Francisco Soastegut found in possession of aguardiente, 1835 (Box 42, Folder 1043)
  - Case against Joaquín Muñoz found in possession of six barrels of aguardiente, 1835 (Box 42, Folder 1044)
  - Petition by Epitacio Ramirez that he be released from prison, 1835 (Box 42, Folder 1045)
  - Casa concerning aguardiente found in possession of Francisco Benites, 1836 (Box 42, Folder 1046)
  - Ramon Altamirano representing the Convent of Reverendos Franciscanos, Cholula, concerning use of finances, 1836 (Box 42, Folder 1047)
  - Petition by Ujenio Gonzalezes that he be released from prison because of innocence, 1836 (Box 42, Folder 1048)
  - Case concerning confiscation of tobacco, 1836 (Box 42, Folder 1049)
  - Action concerning petition by judge of Acatlán for a scribe and ordinance, 1837 (Box 42, Folder 1050)
  - Case against the scribes of the 1st and 2nd tribunal of Amozoc, 1837 (Box 42, Folder 1051)
  - Inventory of the estate of the late Juan María Loudino, 1837 (Box 42, Folder 1052)
  - Certificate of the termination of a case concerning Antonio Torres, 1837 (Box 42, Folder 1053)
  - Petition by Santiago Vivianco that he be released from prison, 1837 (Box 42, Folder 1054)
  - Case concerning payment of parochial rights for the funeral of Manuel Joaquín Lardizabal, 1837 - 1840 (Box 42, Folder 1055)
  - Action initiated by José Mariano Torres' (scribe) question concerning execution of instruments, 1837 - 1841 (Box 42, Folder 1056)
  - Petition by Joaquín Miguél Gallegos that he be permitted to move to Acabingo, 1838 (Box 42, Folder 1057)
  - Decree by the president concerning the case presented by Manuel Zozaya y Ovio, 1839 (Box 42, Folder 1058)
  - Francisco del Valle vs. Cristóbal Melo, 1839 - 1840 (Box 42, Folder 1059)
  - Inventory of and decrees concerning the estate of Isabel López de Alcivar, 1839 - 1841 (Box 42, Folder 1060)
  - Case against the judge of the peace of Huaxealeca for infractions, 1839 - 1848 (Box 42, Folder 1061)
  - José Manuel Hernández vs. José de San Elias concerning a sum of money, 1840 (Box 43, Folder 1062)
  - Case against Joaquín Luna, discovered collecting lottery, 1840 (Box 43, Folder 1063)
  - Petition by José María Vega representing Manuel Dominguez concerning injustices to him, 1840 (Box 43, Folder 1064)
  - Manuel Ignacio Loayza, executor for José Vicente vs. Francisco Calderón concerning mill waters, 1840 - 1842 (Box 43, Folder 1065)
  - Petition by Francisco Asotla that he be released from prison to support his mother, 1841 (Box 43, Folder 1066)
  - Petition by Antonio Gebara concerning the case against him, 1841 (Box 43, Folder 1067)
  - Confiscation of tobacco form José Cristóbal Navarro, 1841 (Box 43, Folder 1068)
  - Agreement concerning José Mariano Torres and procedure of the Mercantile Court, 1841 (Box 43, Folder 1069)
  - Confiscation of tobacco from Ambrosio Cervantes, José Ana Muñoz and Wenceslao González, 1841 - 1842 (Box 43, Folder 1070)
  - Subrogation of capital by the executor for Antonio de Ureta in favor of Pascual Rodríguez de Alconedo, 1841-1848 (Box 43, Folder 1071)
  - Decrees concerning the division of the estate of Manuel Abad y Gueipo, 1842 (Box 43, Folder 1072)
  - Action concerning the deposit of the estate of Pedro Nolasco Arriaga, 1842 (Box 43, Folder 1073)
  - Petition by Manuel Arroyo requesting the chaplaincy founded by Gerónimo de Ayala, 1842 (Box 43, Folder 1074)
  - José Ignacio Castilla concerning the division of the estate of the late Juan Mariano Dominguez, 1842 (Box 43, Folder 1075)
  - Action to inform José María Urrieta of the termination of his commission, 1842 (Box 43, Folder 1076)
  - Petition by Fray José de Jesús María Valenzuela concerning his case, 1842 (Box 43, Folder 1077)
  - Mariano Alvarez vs. the executors of Andrés Fuentes, 1842 - 1846 (Box 43, Folder 1078)
  - José María Melgarejo vs. Juan Nepomuceno Veliz concerning a sum of money, 1844 - 1845 (Box 43, Folder 1079)
  - Petition by María Joséfa Campa that she be released from prison, 1845 (Box 43, Folder 1080)
  - Petition of José María Perez Duslaguer, parish of Ansosoz, 1845 (Box 43, Folder 1081)
  - Petition by José Antonio Hernandes concerning a debt owed to Colonel Nicolás Swiane, 1845 (Box 43, Folder 1082)
  - Case concerning the confiscation of tobacco from the Hacienda Sra. Santa Ana, 1845 (Box 43, Folder 1083)
  - Case concerning the confiscation of a clandestine organ, in San Francisco Caxhuacan, 1845 - 1846 (Box 43, Folder 1084)
  - Case concerning the rent administrator of Zacatlán, for infringing on Art. 43, 1845 - 1846 (Box 43, Folder 1085)
  - Case presented by Juan García and Juan Fuentes concerning cattle, 1852 (Box 43, Folder 1086)
  - Concerning the judge of Tuxpan's dismissing of the First Court, 1852 (Box 43, Folder 1087)
  - Case concerning confiscation of salt, found in possession of Pascual Jiménez, 1854 (Box 43, Folder 1088)
  - Luis Losano vs. Ignacio Guerra Manzanares, judge of Chalchicomula, 1855 - 1856 (Box 44, Folder 1089)
  - Testimony of the contract between José Durante and Tomás Marshall, 1856 (Box 44, Folder 1090)
  - Meeting concerning the estate of Felipe Angulo, 1859 (Box 44, Folder 1091)